NAMITA MANOHAR

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- (919) 710-0364
- www.linkedin.com/in/namita-manohar
- github.com/namitamanohar

PROJECTS

·Nutshell React

A social media dashboard that allows the user to register, login, add events, articles, tasks and friends along with CRUD functionality

DigiPlan

A web application created for students to organize upcoming events along with requesting a tutoring session and absent request. The teacher side of the web app allows for requests to be approved and announcements to be made.

Bangazon

In iaculis nunc sed augue lacus viverra. Mi tempus imperdiet nulla malesuada pellentesque elit.

Back End Capstone

In iaculis nunc sed augue lacus viverra. Mi tempus imperdiet nulla malesuada pellentesque elit.

ABOUT ME

I decided to become a developer after teaching 3 years of computer science at the high school level. After simultaneously teaching myself and my students basic coding, my curiosity in this field peaked. I found the problem solving nature of coding to be intellectually rewarding. I am passionate about increasing diversity and representation in the technology field especially after teaching students of color computer science in a field dominated by one race. Nashville Software School was a program that had been on my mind for some time after hearing about it from friends and word of mouth. I decided to make the leap this past November and am looking forward to becoming a member of a software development team.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | 2019-2020

- •Intensive 6 month full-time full stack development bootcamp that combines learning in both individual and team based projects.
- •Tech stack: Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, C#, .net

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHER

RePublic High School | 2016-2019

- •Taught an introductory computer science course designed to prepare 9th graders for AP Computer Science Principles. Differentiated and created materials that were rigorous and engaging
- •Taught basic HTML, CSS, and JavaScript using CodePen and mobile application design using App Lab, a learning too based in JavaScript. Covered Javascript concepts of variables, functions, and conditionals and basic design principles
- •Taught curriculum that was on a platform accessed by students on chrome-books. Created material to go along with this and modified existing curriculum to make it more accessible to students
- •Collaborated with computer science teachers the middle school level to create aligned content
- •Coached by academic and behavior coach to make sure classroom was aligned to standards and behavior guidelines of school
- •Certified in high school math 9-12 in the state of Tennessee

GLOBAL LEADERSHIP ADVENTURES MENTOR

Costa Rica | 2018

- •Led two groups of about 20 high school students on a service learning program in Costa Rica for a duration of ten days each developing their leadership, service skills, and cultural understanding
- •Assured that students were safe and immersed in experience
- •Fostered relationships with students and the communityshowing them the importance of service and leadership

DISTRICT CAMPAIGN COORDINATOR

ENC STEM 2016

•Worked to recruit students from Weldon City Schools from 9th to 12th for a three-week long summer program called ENC STEM helping them with their application and talking to families•Worked with program directors to check in with how recruiting was going

HIGH SCHOOL MATH TEACHER

WELDON CITY SCHOOLS 2014-1016

- •Taught high school math as a Teach For America Corps Member and was also a member of the school improvement team
- •Created rigorous and differentiated curriculum for students in Math 2, Math 3 and ACT Prep•Tutored students after school that were behind or that wanted extra enrichment

TEACH FOR AMERICA CORPS MEMBER

EASTERN NORTH CAROLINA 2014-1016

- •Selected from a competitive pool to join national teacher corps of recent college graduates and professionals who commit two years to teach in urban and rural public schools.
- •Participated in intensive summer training program to develop the skills and knowledge needed to lead students to academic achievement
- .•Engaged in a full schedule of professional development activities, including seminars in instructional planning, classroom management, learning theory, literacy, and diversity training.

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL 2019-2020

Full Stack Software developer

UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA 2014

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry